# **Pranjal Nanavaty**

pranjalnanavaty@gmail.com Cell: +91-760 085 6599 2/9 R.H.B. Colony Goverdhan Vilas Udaipur(Raj.), India 313001

#### **Profile**

Passion for design, problem solving, and hands-on development along with solid understanding of data structures and algorithms.

Effective research, analysis and communication skills. Pragmatic and adaptable outlook. Knowledge of Accountancy, Banking and Finance.

Languages - C, C++, Javascript, Ruby

Skills

Frameworks - Ruby on Rails, Express, Loopback, React Native

Library - React

Database - PostgreSQL, Oracle 9i, MongoDB

### Full Stack **Developer**

Jun. 2016 - Present

Working at **Tata Consultancy Services Ltd.** with the **Research** and Innovation Infrastructure Team (CTO Team) to develop web apps and provide solution to the upcoming innovations by various teams.

## Work **Experience**

Present work involves back-end development using Ruby on Rails which is used to create RESTful APIs to be rendered by React, which is used for Front-end development.

#### Front-end and **Mobile Developer** - Intern

Jan. 2016 - May 2016

Summer Internship at **Playpower Labs Pvt. Ltd.** which aimed at development of a Learning Management System(LMS) called Lyearn.

The tasks were UI component development for the website which was built using React. The mobile development involved-Android Native component development using Android Studio and implementing the UI using React Native.

**Nirma University** 

2012 - 2016

Bachelor of Technology (B.Tech.), Computer Engineering

**PPI** - 7.31

#### Education

M.M.P.S. 2011

All India Senior School Certificate Examination (AISSCE)

Percentage - 79.00

	<b>M.M.P.S</b> 2009	All India Secondary School Examination (AISSE) <b>Percentage</b> - 81.60
Awards	2016 2015 Techno- 2015 2014	Star of the Learners Group at TCS Initial Learning Program 3rd runner-up in Zeta - An Innovation Initiative at TCS 1st Position in Web-o-Mania (Website Development) at the National Level -Management Colloquium – NU-TECH Member of 1st runner-up Team Faculty Cup(Cricket), Nirma University Member of the winning team Faculty Cup(Cricket), Nirma University Member of the winning team Nirma Cup(Cricket), Nirma University